<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nuku&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nuku&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:54:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nayibor.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Library for parsing iso8583 messages in erlang</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/c33083b29ef6e62daebc9459653f84b9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/c33083b29ef6e62daebc9459653f84b9/</guid>
      <description>i have been working on an iso8583 parsing library. its written in erlang but can be used in erlang,elixir,lfe,etc.. basically all beam languages. this library can be used for packing and unpacking iso8583 financial messages. It accepts a specification file which contains info about fields,mti,bitmap for your messages. The specification has info such as header length for various fields,padding info for fields,etc&amp;hellip; This specification information is then used for packing/unpacking iso8583 formatted messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying code with git and apache</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/deploying-code-with-git-and-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/deploying-code-with-git-and-apache/</guid>
      <description>Today we are going to talk about how to deploy our code to our testing server or production server using git/apache. In this scenario git will be taking the place of the tradional method of using ftp servers to upload code to a server.
We will get to know how to
 configure a remote git repository so it checks out data to a web root location configure apache and create an apache conf file that will enable communication between the git repository and apache setup authenticaton in apache for git events push to remote repository and see files in web root  Let&amp;rsquo;s hit the road!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming languages as web template languages</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/0cbce1a3a305b158373f04c7e4c579dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:52:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/0cbce1a3a305b158373f04c7e4c579dc/</guid>
      <description>Web templating languages!!. Don&amp;rsquo;t we love em.
Every one has their favourite but a common denominator among them all is that they make our work as web developers easier by giving us separation of concerns between data and content as well as lots of other advantages. A fancy term for web templating languages is a web template system.
From Wikipedia a Web template system is defined as
 A web template system uses a template processor to combine web templates to form finished web pages, possibly using some data source to customize the pages or present a large amount of content on similar-looking pages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing iso8583 messages Part 2</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/4948d52595d68beab6dd3a919db6d115/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/4948d52595d68beab6dd3a919db6d115/</guid>
      <description>Today we will be showing how to extract the various components out of an iso string. The combination of a tcp server as well as code to extract the iso message components and send it for further processing is what is popularly called an interface server in payment processing . Specifically the components we are interested in are
the next step is to get the bitmap which is a hexadecimal(base 16 number)which starts from the fifth digit and is either 8 or 16 in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing iso8583 messages Part 1</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/73e0ec2ac943bfecb47acbe2e603f814/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 07:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/73e0ec2ac943bfecb47acbe2e603f814/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iso8583  message structure</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/ddf349de5c9c5cf29af2e17bc71724b8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 07:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/ddf349de5c9c5cf29af2e17bc71724b8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagination using backbone.js and underscore template</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/f60a18aff854a9e6a287de1898f22a62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 02:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/f60a18aff854a9e6a287de1898f22a62/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cakephp 2.6.7  rawQuery bug</title>
      <link>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/a0a580a0696d4382cab7314f832df7c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 13:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nayibor.github.io/posts/a0a580a0696d4382cab7314f832df7c3/</guid>
      <description>return $this-&amp;gt;execute($sql, $params);   This was accepting two parameters instead of three and due to this was mistaking the $params value for the options value thus query was not run .query was being run as public function rawQuery($sql, $params = array()) {
     $this-&amp;gt;took = $this-&amp;gt;numRows = false;
      return $this-&amp;gt;execute($sql, $params);    }Instead of public function rawQuery($sql, $params = array()) {</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
